Nowhere is safe.
Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows: Part 1 is a
adventure, fantasy film directed by David Yates.
Harry, Ron and Hermione walk away from their last year at Hogwarts to find and destroy the
remaining Horcruxes, putting an end to Voldemort's bid for immortality.
But with Harry's beloved Dumbledore dead and Voldemort's unscrupulous Death
Eaters on the loose, the world is more dangerous than ever.
Harry Potter, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Hermione Granger, played by Emma Watson.
Ron Weasley, played by Rupert Grint.
Dobby (voice), played by Toby Jones.
Bellatrix Lestrange, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Severus Snape, played by Alan Rickman.
Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 1 is a 2010 fantasy film
directed by David Yates from a screenplay by Steve Kloves.
The first of two cinematic parts based on the 2007 novel
Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows by J.
Rowling, it is the sequel to Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince (2009)
and the seventh instalment in the Harry Potter film series.
The film stars Daniel Radcliffe as Harry Potter, with Rupert Grint and Emma Watson,
respectively, reprising roles as Harry's best friends Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger.
The story follows Harry Potter, who has been asked by Dumbledore to find and
destroy Lord Voldemort's secret to immortality – the Horcruxes.
Filming began on 19 February 2009 and was completed on 12 June 2010.
It was released in 2D cinemas and IMAX formats in the United Kingdom and
in the United States on 19 November 2010, by Warner Bros.
The film received positive reviews with critics praising the
performances, cinematography, visual effects and musical score.
In the film's worldwide opening weekend, Part 1 grossed $330 million, the third-highest in the
series, and the highest opening of 2010, as well as the eighth-highest of all time.
With a worldwide gross of $960 million, Part 1 became the third-highest-grossing film of 2010, the tenth highest-grossing
film of all time at the time  and the third-highest-grossing Harry Potter film in terms of worldwide totals.
The film was nominated for many awards, including the Academy
Award for Best Art Direction and Best Visual Effects.
The film was followed by the concluding entry, Harry Potter
and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2 in 2011.
The film explores themes of witch, friendship,
london, england, corruption, escape.